<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>janmabandha</title>
  <subtitle>by Kiran Akkineni</subtitle>
  <link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-07-23T16:27:02.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>janmabandha</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Outsourced management of startup stock option plans</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Outsourced-management-of-startup-stock-option-plans/2016/07/23/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Outsourced-management-of-startup-stock-option-plans/2016/07/23/</id>
    <published>2016-07-23T16:27:02.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-23T16:27:02.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;Adverse-selection-vs-dead-equity&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Adverse-selection-vs-dead-equity&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Adverse selection vs. dead equity&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Adverse selection vs. dead equity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In theory, startup options can make sense for employees given the risk / reward tradeoffs,
  but the choice is much less simple when accounting for structural elements in option
  grant fine print. For example, employees typically have 90 or less days to exercise
  vested shares when they leave the company. This can represent a huge cost for most
  employees in exchange for no immediate cash gain (unless the startup happens to
  be in the process of completing a liquidity event). &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some companies have begun to opt into providing significantly longer post-termination
  exercise periods, but this has implications as well for employees who chose not
  to leave the company (and future employees), in the form of a gradually increasing
  dilution of the equity pool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an environment where more companies are opting to forego exiting (given ease of
  raising private money, being profitable but unwilling to deal with public markets,
  or a host of other reasons), decisions around the structure of an option plan can
  have big implications. Either unengaged / unqualified employees choose to stick
  around for a long time if the plan is too strict, or they create a massive dilutive
  liability if the plan is too lax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Focus-vs-Education&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Focus-vs-Education&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Focus vs. Education&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Focus vs. Education&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most startups won’t be profitable at the time an option plan is devised, meaning
  the founders / executives have bigger fish to fry than to build a complex customizabe
  option plan that works for every employee. Building a business, hiring, finding
  a market, and creating a great product represent work that already takes a great
  deal of time and sacrifice, so even with the best intentions in mind, founders
  are unlikely to focus on this problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many startup employees don’t know enough about equity compensation (especially stock
  options) to ask for the provisions which would best fit their individual situation,
  or to prepare for a given outcome (such as how to pay for vested shares when exiting
  the company). Perversely, there is a disincentive for founders to help educate
  employees, as this could reduce the company’s future optionality in the form of
  fundraising, future hires, the founders’ own compensation, etc. Even if employees
  were educated on these things, it’s unlikely that the company would customize the
  offer for any but the most senior employees. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So there isn’t time to build the perfectly complex plan, and there isn’t enough education
  to ensure employees make the best decisions for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Outsourced-management&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Outsourced-management&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Outsourced management&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Outsourced management&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a few inputs from a startup’s management, would it be possible for an outsourced
  manager to create more custom plans for employees?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the employer:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Share of equity pool allocated to ESOP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;General comp bands by position&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Value of current common shares&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expected cash risks for the business (is it monetizing, growth rates, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liquidity event likelihood&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employee base and hiring rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the employee:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Existing liquidity risks (current savings, debt, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Financial risk tolerance&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Employment lifestage and flight risk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expectations around the business&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over time could the outsourced manager scalably educate employees and manage custom
  option plans, from offer through to exercise (including during employee termination)?
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could more commodity management and financial products be offered to employees over
  time as the outsourced manager scaled?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Adverse-selection-vs-dead-equity&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Adverse-selection-vs-dead-equity&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Adverse selection vs. dea
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Ideas/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Startup ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startup-ideas/"/>
    
      <category term="Startups" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startups/"/>
    
      <category term="Employee stock options" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Employee-stock-options/"/>
    
      <category term="ESO" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/ESO/"/>
    
      <category term="Management plan" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Management-plan/"/>
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Beats, Rhymes, and Life</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/beats-rhymes-and-life-MJ/2016/06/19/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/beats-rhymes-and-life-MJ/2016/06/19/</id>
    <published>2016-06-19T19:01:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-25T16:18:20.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;by-Matt-Johnson&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#by-Matt-Johnson&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;by Matt Johnson&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;by
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-johnson-9b97564&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Matt Johnson&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ego is a mofo…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;‘What-Really-Goes-On’&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#‘What-Really-Goes-On’&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;‘What Really Goes On’&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;‘What Really Goes On’&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my favorite Phife Dog rhymes is “Ego/I’m on my own jock skill/Cuz if I don’t
  say I’m the best/Tell me who the hell will”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founding teams are filled with egos. You probably already know that. Because you’re
  fucking awesome and know everything about everything. We all do. Ego is why an
  entrepreneur thinks their idea is a winner. Ego is why an entrepreneur runs through
  walls when others give up. Ego is why an entrepreneur risks it for the biscuit.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(You already know where I’m going with this)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ego is also a huge source of conflict. Building anything requires communication and
  compromise. Ego prevents both.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I’m right and you say the same thing as me, but you get the credit, what’s my
  reaction? Ego says “f- that guy!”. Ego strength, on the other hand, says “I’m happy
  someone I respect agrees. I must be on the right path.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have an idea of how to reach a goal, and you have a different idea of how to
  reach a goal, what’s my reaction? Ego says “f- that guy!”. Ego strength says “I
  respect your process, and since you’re leading the effort, I trust you.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;‘Keep-It-Movin’&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#‘Keep-It-Movin’&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;‘Keep It Movin’&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;‘Keep It Movin’&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our product leads are hyper talented. They know the subject matter, they know the
  technology, and they have a clear vision of where we need to be. I trust them explicitly
  to get us where we need to be. That’s why they own product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, ego and ego strength collided. During a discussion about our product with
  the product team, I wasn’t happy with the speed with which we were progressing.
  As a CSPO and terrible amateur product manager, I had envisioned a very specific
  process. This was not the process the product team was using in this specific conversation,
  and I didn’t think that was right. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ego reared its infinitely ugly head, and I lashed out. I wanted them to follow my
  process, the scrum product owner process, moving forward. “We will not build our
  product on a shitty foundation. How the hell are we going to attract the engineering
  talent we need without properly written epics? It’s critical that we use my process,
  the approved process, the common process, the correct process from the beginning.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of reacting to my idiocy, one of our product leads stopped my rant and explained
  what he was actually doing. He walked me through his approach, and assured me that
  the deliverables would be what I expected. By simply acknowledging my concerns
  and explaining his approach, he mitigated my anxiety and reinforced his competency.
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ego strength won. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I swear no more Tribe references (for now).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Company and product will be revealed soon. Patience is a virtue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h4 id=&quot;by-Matt-Johnson&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#by-Matt-Johnson&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;by Matt Johnson&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;by
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy and business" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy-and-business/"/>
    
      <category term="Data and Tech" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Data-and-Tech/"/>
    
      <category term="Perspectives" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Perspectives/"/>
    
      <category term="Matt Johnson" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Matt-Johnson/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly reads, week of June 13 2016</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jun13/2016/06/18/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jun13/2016/06/18/</id>
    <published>2016-06-18T14:10:59.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-18T15:53:13.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Product-management&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Product-management&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Product management&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Product management&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.intercom.io/first-rule-prioritization-no-snacking/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;THE FIRST RULE OF PRIORITIZATION: NO SNACKING&lt;/a&gt; by Des Traynor
  &lt;br&gt;// The ability to find and prioritize low-effort-high-impact work diminishes as
  organizations mature. Many organizations tend to shift into prioritizing low-effort-low-impact
  work as a result, which rarely creates long-term value. Focus on high-effort-high-impact
  work, since this is where the value lies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://bgr.com/2016/05/25/amazon-echo-vs-siri-voice-recognition/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Why Amazon’s Echo is better to talk to than Siri&lt;/a&gt; by Chris Smith
  &lt;br&gt;// The Echo team is completely focused on building a great voice-only in-home assistant,
  allowing them not to have to worry about or prioritize mobility, UI, or a slew
  of other things that the Apple / Siri team has to consider. As a result, they’ve
  produced a great always-on, high responsive product with a great user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Data-and-Tech&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Data-and-Tech&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Data and Tech&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Data and Tech&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/googles-go-to-market-gap/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;How bot-to-bot could soon replace APIs&lt;/a&gt; by Niko Nelissen
  &lt;br&gt;// Interesting hypothesis that bots (bot-to-bot and bot-to-bot-to-consumer), could
  be the next evolution from APIs. This would be heavily dependent on the advancement
  of technologies that this evolution would rely on of course (NLP, ML, AI, etc.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketingland.com/facebooks-deeptext-near-human-understanding-people-posts-179458&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Facebook’s DeepText has “near-human” understanding of people’s posts&lt;/a&gt; by Tim
  Peterson
  &lt;br&gt;// Accelerating the evolution of NLP by eschewing traditional methods in favor
  of a character-based method, which uses massive swaths of available data to learn
  from observed relationships between characters, context, and sentiment. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Business-and-Strategy&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Business-and-Strategy&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Business and Strategy&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Business and Strategy&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2016/may/12/facebook-free-basics-india-zuckerberg&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The inside story of Facebook’s biggest setback&lt;/a&gt; by Rahul Bhatia
  &lt;br&gt;// Many things went wrong here. One big lesson is to spend effort learning about
  your customers and their problems rather than imposing your solution on your perception
  of their problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2016/05/24/spotify-financials/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Spotify’s Financial Results Reinforce Just How Broken the Music Business Is&lt;/a&gt;
  by Mathew Ingram
  &lt;br&gt;// Despite rampant growth and engagement, Spotify’s costs-to-serve may be too high
  for the company to reach profitability into the future. ‘Of every dollar that Spotify
  brings in the door in revenues, about 85 cents goes right back out the door again
  in the form of payments to the music industry.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/the-curse-of-culture/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Curse of Culture&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Thompson
  &lt;br&gt;// Couple notable quotes:
  &lt;br&gt;‘As with most such things, culture is one of a company’s most powerful assets right
  until it isn’t: the same underlying assumptions that permit an organization to
  scale massively constrain the ability of that same organization to change direction.
  More distressingly, culture prevents organizations from even knowing they need
  to do so.’ ‘Leadership is now the ability to step outside the culture that created
  the leader and to start evolutionary change processes that are more adaptive. This
  ability to perceive the limitations of one’s own culture and to evolve the culture
  adaptively is the essence and ultimate challenge of leadership.’&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Product-management&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Product-management&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Product management&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Product management&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
 
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Weekly reads" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Weekly-reads/"/>
    
      <category term="Articles" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Articles/"/>
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy and business" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy-and-business/"/>
    
      <category term="Data and Tech" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Data-and-Tech/"/>
    
      <category term="Perspectives" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Perspectives/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hard to Earn</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/hard-to-earn-MJ/2016/06/12/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/hard-to-earn-MJ/2016/06/12/</id>
    <published>2016-06-12T19:00:00.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-25T16:18:35.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h4 id=&quot;by-Matt-Johnson&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#by-Matt-Johnson&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;by Matt Johnson&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;by
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/matt-johnson-9b97564&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Matt Johnson&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SO, I’m founding a start-up. Well, technically I’m founding a start-up with a team
  of talented contributors. We’re going to conquer the world by using [technology]
  to deliver [adjective] outcomes for [customer segment] in [industry]. It’s going
  to be amazing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;‘Intro-The-First-Step-’&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#‘Intro-The-First-Step-’&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;‘Intro (The First Step)’&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;‘Intro (The First Step)’&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what’s awesome about start-ups? Everyone genuinely wants to get involved
  with your company in some way, and everyone has an opinion on how to build it.
  “Focus on these customers.” “Don’t forget to do X,Y,Z.” “Beware of these pitfalls.”
  Etc. etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing, though: All of that guidance and opinions and parables and bullshit
  out there starts once you’ve actually founded the company. You can find resources
  on product development, finding customers, raising money, blah, blah, blah. Very
  few people talk about how to get to the starting line. The “holy shit, we’re going
  to start a real company with real responsibilities!” starting line.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where are the mentors who want to help you incorporate? Who want to help you pick
  your founders? Who want to help you build your board, without requiring a seat?
  Who love employer ID numbers, and taxes, and choosing the correct fucking insurance?
  No one eagerly steps up to help with the hard, boring, unsexy, soul-crushing, yet
  absolutely critical, decisions required to get started. Unless they want a piece
  of the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How many companies fail at this stage? Is this the plight of the COO? What challenges
  are next? Does any of it really matter?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;‘ALONGWAYTOGO’&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#‘ALONGWAYTOGO’&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;‘ALONGWAYTOGO’&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;‘ALONGWAYTOGO’&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitching aside, our technology can win (I’ve been told start-up rule #2 is ‘Always
  believe’). I really, truly, believe that (see previous sentence). Can our team
  win? Let’s find out…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Matt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post-script:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I hope to post with some regular cadence, but no guarantees. Sorry.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I know how to use Google. Please do not send me anything from the first 2 pages
    of search results to ‘help out’. I respect your effort, so save those links for
    a more appropriate time when I’m ready to digest your guidance fully. I promise
    you’ll have that opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll reveal our product soon.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I know founders and start-up blogs are played out like your mom’s haircut. Or two-tone
    down goose. Also, you couldn’t converse if you had fucking React Juice (R.I.P.
    Diggy, s/o Grandmama).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I know I can be a know-it-all. It’s on my self-improvement list.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes, those are rap-nerd easter eggs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h4 id=&quot;by-Matt-Johnson&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#by-Matt-Johnson&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;by Matt Johnson&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;by
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy and business" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy-and-business/"/>
    
      <category term="Data and Tech" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Data-and-Tech/"/>
    
      <category term="Perspectives" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Perspectives/"/>
    
      <category term="Matt Johnson" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Matt-Johnson/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Anonymous content platform</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Anonymous-content-platform/2016/05/29/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Anonymous-content-platform/2016/05/29/</id>
    <published>2016-05-29T21:26:41.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-19T21:13:37.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;Whistleblower-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Whistleblower-content&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Whistleblower content&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Whistleblower content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, whistleblowers can rely on platforms which use anonymising networks to
  allow submission of sensitive information (the leaked content cannot easily be
  traced back to the content provider). In order to use the network, the whistleblower
  needs to download software (i.e. browser) and access services, so some basic technical
  skill is required, and UX is not well-evolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;UX issues aside, once the information has been submitted, it needs to be distributed.
  For whistleblowers,
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GlobaLeaks&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;platforms&lt;/a&gt; exist which allow for distribution of anonymously leaked content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Gawker-type-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Gawker-type-content&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Gawker-type content&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Gawker-type content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gawker&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Gawker&lt;/a&gt; is a highly publicized and well-read gossip publication currently being
  sued by multiple plaintiffs, related to published articles associated with the
  plaintiffs. A recent lawsuit in particular, by Hulk Hogan, has gained notoriety
  due to Hogan’s
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2016/05/26/business/dealbook/peter-thiel-tech-billionaire-reveals-secret-war-with-gawker.html?_r=0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;financial backing by Peter Thiel&lt;/a&gt; and Thiel’s potential motive for revenge.
  The costs of defending the suit may put Gawker at risk of insolvency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Anonymous-platform&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Anonymous-platform&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Anonymous platform?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Anonymous platform?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are options for whistleblowers, do similar widely-used options exist
  for anonymous submission and distribution of ‘less serious’ content? For example
  an anonymous content platform for news, rumors, anonymous memoirs, etc.?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since these ‘less serious’ users may intend to produce content with the purpose of
  receiving payment, could payment mechanisms be created such that these users could
  be paid immediately and near-anonymously based on pre-existing terms (i.e. number
  of views, clicks, etc.)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could a better user experience be created for the providers, which allows for management
  of submission, distribution, and incoming payments?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would a front-end need to exist, or could existing distribution platforms be leveraged
  once the content had been anonymously ingested?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Technologies&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Technologies&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Technologies&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Technologies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tor_anonymity_network&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Tor&lt;/a&gt; – Tor / Onion Services allows for the near-anonymous submission of content,
  such that the content provider has limited vulnerability with regards to being
  identified&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethereum&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Ethereum&lt;/a&gt; – Ethereum is a
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Block_chain_database&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;blockchain&lt;/a&gt; platform that enables execution of smart contracts using ether,
  a cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Whistleblower-content&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Whistleblower-content&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Whistleblower content&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Whistleblower conten
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Ideas/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Startup ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startup-ideas/"/>
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Media" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Media/"/>
    
      <category term="Anonymous publishing" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Anonymous-publishing/"/>
    
      <category term="Tor" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Tor/"/>
    
      <category term="Ethereum" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Ethereum/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly reads, week of May 23 2016</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-May23/2016/05/28/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-May23/2016/05/28/</id>
    <published>2016-05-28T14:57:40.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-28T15:44:05.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Data-and-Tech&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Data-and-Tech&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Data and Tech&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Data and Tech&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/the-coinbase-blog/ethereum-is-the-forefront-of-digital-currency-5300298f6c75#.nb3r0grfl&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Ethereum is the Forefront of Digital Currency&lt;/a&gt; by Fred Ehrsam
  &lt;br&gt;// Bitcoin proved the concepts behind blockchain and decentralized transactional
  networks, but Ethereum may be a better path forward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ampproject.org/docs/support/faqs.html#what-is-the-accelerated-mobile-pages-project&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Accelerated Mobile Pages Project&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;// One of the ways Google aims to circumvent Facebook and Apple’s app ecosystem.
  Mobile-optimized, for high speed and exploration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Strategy-and-business&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Strategy-and-business&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Strategy and business&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Strategy and business&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/googles-go-to-market-gap/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Google’s Go-To Market Gap&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Thompson
  &lt;br&gt;// Hypothesis is that Google is the rare company that succeeded (immensely) almost
  purely from having superior technology, rather than business development, operational
  execution, marketing, product strategy, etc. Moving forward, this may present challenges
  to the company’s ability to compete with superior businesses, in spite of better
  tech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/wonk/wp/2016/05/19/the-apple-industrys-strange-savior/?tid=sm_tw&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;A clever tweak to how apples are sold is making everyone eat more of them&lt;/a&gt; by
  Roberto A Ferdman
  &lt;br&gt;// Selling apples pre-sliced had a massive impact on fresh apple consumption. By
  pre-slicing, children were much more willing to eat apples for lunch, as this reduced
  seemingly miniscule challenges to eating apples. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://tomtunguz.com/leading-predictor-saas-series-a-valuation/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Leading Predictor Of Series A Valuation For SaaS Companies&lt;/a&gt; by Tomasz Tunguz
  &lt;br&gt;// ‘The data underscores why building a great product is the first order of business
  for a startup and why developing great customer success should be the second order
  of business. Many founders do this instinctively, and develop a cadre of reference
  customers.’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Perspectives&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Perspectives&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Perspectives&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Perspectives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.vox.com/2016/5/23/11704246/wealth-inequality-cartoon&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;This cartoon explains how the rich got rich and the poor got poor&lt;/a&gt; by Alvin
  Chang
  &lt;br&gt;// Strong hypothesis that wealth inequality is influenced by source of income (investment
  for upper classes, paychecks for lower classes), and regulatory impacts (i.e. tax
  policy) on those income sources. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://mobile.nytimes.com/2016/05/22/upshot/are-you-successful-if-so-youve-already-won-the-lottery.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Are You Successful? If So, You’ve Already Won the Lottery&lt;/a&gt; by Robert H Frank
  &lt;br&gt;// Grit, effort, and ingenuity are rarely undervalued when assigning credit for
  success, but humans tend to grossly underestimate the impact of luck. Reflecting
  on one’s good fortune tends to generate a greater willingness to contribute to
  others’ success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/evolution-of-anxiety&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Evolution of Anxiety: Why We Worry and What to Do About It&lt;/a&gt; by James Clear
  &lt;br&gt;// Although humans have evolved for a Immediate Return Environment, most of us
  must operate within a Delayed Return Environment, which in turn generates anxiety.
  Converting anxiety-induxing long-term issues into measurable (and smaller) tasks
  can significantly alleviate anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/evolution-of-anxiety&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Mongol hordes gave up on conquering Europe due to wet weather&lt;/a&gt; by Conor Gearin
  &lt;br&gt;// Mongol hordes, which innovated upon war through the integration of cavalry,
  may have retreated from central Europe primarily because of a swamp-like environment
  in Hungary in the mid 1200s. Because the army was unable to provide pasture for
  horses in Hungary, much of the disruptive advantage they had come to rely upon
  disappeared. Not dissimilar to Napoleon’s army in wintertime Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Data-and-Tech&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Data-and-Tech&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Data and Tech&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Data and Tech&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://me
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Weekly reads" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Weekly-reads/"/>
    
      <category term="Articles" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Articles/"/>
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy and business" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy-and-business/"/>
    
      <category term="Data and Tech" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Data-and-Tech/"/>
    
      <category term="Perspectives" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Perspectives/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly reads, week of May 16 2016</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-May16/2016/05/22/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-May16/2016/05/22/</id>
    <published>2016-05-22T22:05:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-28T15:44:01.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;Strategy-and-business&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Strategy-and-business&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Strategy and business&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Strategy and business&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slideshare.net/mokriya/what-is-product-management-61353217&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;What is Product Management&lt;/a&gt; by Mokriya
  &lt;br&gt;// Some perspectives on the function and its future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Data-and-Tech&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Data-and-Tech&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Data and Tech&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Data and Tech&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://andrewchen.co/breaking-down-671-million-push-notifications-by-hour/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;What 671 million push notifications say about how people spend their day&lt;/a&gt; by
  Andrew Chen
  &lt;br&gt;// Lots of interesting takeaways here. Amazing how tight the spread between sends
  and opens are. And although not surprising, it’s also cool to see how much greater
  work-time usage exists for mobile apps vs. other media.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://fivethirtyeight.com/features/the-sumo-matchup-centuries-in-the-making/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Sumo Matchup Centuries In The Making&lt;/a&gt; by Benjamin Morris
  &lt;br&gt;// Amazing how much data has been collected on sumo matches over centuries…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2016/05/instant-apps-google-aims-make-web-apps-one/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;With Instant Apps, Google Aims to Make the Web and Apps One&lt;/a&gt; by Cade Metz
  &lt;br&gt;// Google has clear incentive to work around the existing app (and app marketplace)
  model by blurring the line between web and apps, through either greatly improving
  the mobile web experience, or making apps more like the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2016/05/the-end-of-code/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Soon We Won’t Program Computers. We’ll Train Them Like Dogs&lt;/a&gt; by Jason Tanz
  &lt;br&gt;// Machine learning makes it significantly more difficult to understand the EXACT
  mechanics behind how computers produce output and make decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;Perspectives&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Perspectives&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Perspectives&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Perspectives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/the-real-problem-with-facebook-and-the-news/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Real Problem With Facebook and the News – Stratechery&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Thompson
  &lt;br&gt;// Shared facts and different perspectives could be an improvement over self-curated
  echo chambers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://zachholman.com/posts/the-new-10-year-vesting-schedule&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The New 10-Year Vesting Schedule&lt;/a&gt; by Zach Holman
  &lt;br&gt;// Startup employees are finding it increasingly difficult to unlock compensation
  (in the form of stock options) generated by their by their contributions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.rawstory.com/2015/04/the-numbers-are-staggering-us-is-world-leader-in-child-poverty/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The numbers are staggering: US is ‘world leader’ in child poverty&lt;/a&gt; by Paul Buchheit
  &lt;br&gt;// The share of kids on foods stamps in the US has increased by over 60% in the
  last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2016/05/my-secret-shame/476415/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Secret Shame of Middle-Class Americans&lt;/a&gt; by Neal Gabler
  &lt;br&gt;// A lot more people are struggling financially than it would seem, possibly driven
  by the democratization of revolving credit in the 80s and 90s, as well as income
  stagnation across many industries.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h1 id=&quot;Strategy-and-business&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Strategy-and-business&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Strategy and business&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Strategy and busines
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Weekly reads" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Weekly-reads/"/>
    
      <category term="Articles" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Articles/"/>
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy and business" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy-and-business/"/>
    
      <category term="Data and Tech" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Data-and-Tech/"/>
    
      <category term="Perspectives" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Perspectives/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Crowdsuing platform</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Crowdsuing-platform/2016/05/21/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Crowdsuing-platform/2016/05/21/</id>
    <published>2016-05-21T19:32:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-26T03:41:02.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;Class-action-challenges&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Class-action-challenges&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Class action / challenges&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Class action / challenges&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Litigation may be fairly easy in modern times (especially for people with the funds
  to sue), but there are still meaningful challenges for individuals suing large
  organizations, especially in cases where these individuals are dependent on said
  large organizations (for examples, employees of large and influential businesses).
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Class action lawsuits tend to make it significantly easier for people to sue businesses
  for similar or shared greivances. Upfront costs are reduced, plaintiffs can be
  represented without being directly involved in the suit, and legal representation
  can be consolidated across plaintiffs. That being said, there are still challenges
  in these types of suits. They need to be certified by a judge, the suits require
  named plaintiffs to step up and start the suit, it’s difficult to select the best
  legal representation, lawyers are incentivized to settle, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Certification-required&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Certification-required&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Certification required&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Certification required&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;from:
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/rules/frcp/rule_23&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Cornell Legal Information Insititute&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(1) the class is so numerous that joinder of all members is impracticable;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(2) there are questions of law or fact common to the class;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(3) the claims or defenses of the representative parties are typical of the claims
  or defenses of the class;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(4) the representative parties will fairly and adequately protect the interests of
  the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Crowdsuing-platform&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Crowdsuing-platform&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Crowdsuing platform?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Crowdsuing platform?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can a platform enable and ensure certification for class action suits?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can a lawsuit be de-risked by enabling better selection (competition) of legal representation
  and coordination by named plaintiffs?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can potential named plaintiffs gain confidence through knowledge of additional willing
  named plaintiffs?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Class-action-challenges&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Class-action-challenges&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Class action / challenges&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Class action
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Ideas/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Startup ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startup-ideas/"/>
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Legal" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Legal/"/>
    
      <category term="Crowdsourcing" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Crowdsourcing/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Outsourced management of startup stock option plans</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Startup-employee-ESO-protection/2016/05/08/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Startup-employee-ESO-protection/2016/05/08/</id>
    <published>2016-05-09T00:46:42.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-07-23T16:33:08.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;Employees-and-risk&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Employees-and-risk&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Employees and risk&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Employees and risk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Early stage employees (usually among 1st 40 hires, or joined before the company is
  unit positive) tend to take on significant time and salary risk when joining startups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of this risk is compensated for by the opportunity to grow and generate impact
  at rates that these employees wouldn’t have been able to achieve in more mature
  businesses. Some of it is through the building of strong relationships forged through
  fire drills, all-nighters, and solving impossible problems. And lastly, some of
  it is compensated by vested equity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the value from the first couple of aforementioned trade-offs are dependent
  on the employees’ own effort and focus. For the third, the equity, a lot is out
  of the their control, especially when it comes to fundraising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Impact-of-raising-capital&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Impact-of-raising-capital&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Impact of raising capital&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Impact of raising capital&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When companies choose to take on funding, they do so for a variety of reasons (staying
  afloat, working capital, new opportunities, fundraising climate, etc.), but they
  rarely consult or involve employees other than executives. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet the impacts of raising more money can have significant impact on one of the major
  reasons that employee give up time, salary, and oftentimes mental well-being to
  work at the company.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;General dilution, preference, protection, increased cash burn, etc. are all ways
  that an employee’s equity stake can be significantly impacted. Aside from dilution,
  employees tend to be very inexperienced with most of the other ways that raising
  money can impact their common equity value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;Stock-option-insurance&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Stock-option-insurance&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Stock option insurance?&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Stock option insurance?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there a way to allow early employees to protect themselves by purchasing some
  form of insurance on the value of their vested shares?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could the insurance provider price the offering well enough to both mimize counterparty
  risk and benefit employees?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is it possible that breakage (from unclaimed insurance or canceled policies) could
  effectively stand in for a counterparty?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h2 id=&quot;Employees-and-risk&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;#Employees-and-risk&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Employees and risk&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Employees and risk&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ea
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Ideas/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Startup ideas" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startup-ideas/"/>
    
      <category term="Startups" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startups/"/>
    
      <category term="Employee stock options" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Employee-stock-options/"/>
    
      <category term="ESO" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/ESO/"/>
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Stock option insurance" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Stock-option-insurance/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly reads, week of January 25 2016</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jan25/2016/01/25/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jan25/2016/01/25/</id>
    <published>2016-01-26T05:25:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-05-27T04:56:46.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kollinz/misused-mobile-ux-patterns-84d2b6930570#.de7e6u954&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Misused mobile UX patterns&lt;/a&gt; by Zoltan Kollin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Experiments show, however, that exposing menu options in a more visible way increases
    engagement, user satisfaction and even revenue’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Basic functionality can be effectively represented by icons but for complex features,
    text labels should be used. (And if you use icons, always have them usability
    tested.)’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onboarding: Promotes progressive onboarding over overlays, because users tend to
    skip intros and tutorials. Empty state / blank slate needs to be simple and intuitive.
    Potentially have less options than once the page starts populating&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More companies are moving towards combining intuitive text with icons for the mobile
    experience →
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://thomasbyttebier.be/blog/the-best-icon-is-a-text-label&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;http://thomasbyttebier.be/blog/the-best-icon-is-a-text-label&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/bridge-collection/the-first-15-seconds-9590d7dabc#.6f3d0e8n1&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The First 15 Seconds&lt;/a&gt; by Scott Belsky&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘An effective hook appeals to short term interests (one’s laziness, vanity, and
    self-interests) that are connected to a long term promise.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘As you build your product or service, bifurcate your approach […] initially, your
    prospective customers are lazy, vain, and selfish.Optimize for the first 15 seconds
    as a compartmentalized project. And then, for the customers that survive the
    first 15 seconds and actually come through the door, build a meaningful experience
    and relationship that lasts a lifetime’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://youarenotsosmart.com/2011/03/25/the-sunk-cost-fallacy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Sunk Cost Fallacy&lt;/a&gt; by David McRaney&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Your decisions are tainted by the emotional investments you accumulate, and the
    more you invest in something the harder it becomes to abandon it’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘When offered a chance to accept or reject a gamble, most people refuse to make
    take a bet unless the possible payoff is around double the potential loss’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘This is the powerful force behind Farmville. Playing Farmville is a commitment
    to a virtual life form. Your neglect has consequences. If you don’t return, your
    investments die and you will feel like you wasted your time, money and effort.
    You must return, sometimes days later, to reap the reward of the time and virtual
    money you are spending now. If you don’t, not only do you not get rewarded, you
    lose your investments’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/how-facebook-squashed-twitter/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;How Facebook Squashed Twitter&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Thompson
  &lt;br&gt;The idea of a “smartphone” that could connect to the Internet and run applications
  was around long before 2007; Apple…stratechery.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘as of 2009, not only was it easier to get started with Facebook, but it was also
    more likely that the service had enough interesting content to ensure most users
    had no desire to look for something better’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘When it comes to “the empty spaces” most people don’t want to do work, but work
    is exactly what Twitter required. You had to know what you were interested in,
    know who to follow based on those interests, and then, to top it all off, you
    had to pick out the parts that you were interested in from a stream of unfiltered
    tweets; Facebook, in contrast, did the work for you’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.samaltman.com/before-growth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Before Growth&lt;/a&gt; by Sam Altman&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘“do any users love our product so much they spontaneously tell other people to
    use it?”’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@satyap/what-s-your-startup-s-superpower-f9392cbba4bc#.34knuvt0c&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;What’s your startup’s superpower?&lt;/a&gt; by Satya Patel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Google is best in the world at search. Facebook is best in the world at building
    a social network. Apple is best in the world at building integrated software
    and hardware for consumers. All of those markets are or were incredibly crowded’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Google knew that to be best in search in needed the best data infrastructure.
    Facebook knew that if it wanted the largest social network it needed a competency
    around growth of that network. And Apple knew that if it wanted to build devices
    for the average consumer, it needed simple and beautiful design’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Once you answer that question, you can focus on the development of that superpower
    rather than on things that make you temporarily different or different in a way
    that is easy to replicate’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2015-12-20/bezos-s-behind-the-scenes-role-in-washington-post-s-web-growth&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Bezos’s Behind-the-Scenes Role in the Washington Post’s Web Growth&lt;/a&gt; by Gerry
  Smith&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘They talk about reducing “cognitive overhead” and “friction” that discourages
    readers from signing up for e-mail newsletters. Bezos calls ideas that could
    upset Post subscribers, like jamming too many ads on a Web page, “reader hostile.”’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Bezos requires Post executives to write lengthy memos outlining their projects
    instead of using PowerPoint presentations, believing that narrative writing forces
    people to think more deeply’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Inside the new newsroom in Washington […] a large screen displays real-time traffic
    statistics of stories on its website. […] Bezos suggested measuring whether readers
    prefer the Post to its rivals. So engineers created a program that takes articles
    from [competitors], strips out their branding, then surveys readers on which
    articles they’d rather read’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2016/01/18/why-big-companies-keep-failing-the-stack-fallacy/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Stack fallacy — Common cause of big companies missing out&lt;/a&gt; by Anshu Sharma&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foundingfuel.com/article/the-fault-in-our-startups/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The fault in our startups&lt;/a&gt; by Haresh Chawla&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@kollinz/misused-mobile-ux-patterns-84d2b6930570#.de7e6u954&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Misused mobile
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Startups" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startups/"/>
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Weekly reads" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Weekly-reads/"/>
    
      <category term="Articles" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Articles/"/>
    
      <category term="Work" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Work/"/>
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly reads, week of January 18 2016</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jan18/2016/01/18/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jan18/2016/01/18/</id>
    <published>2016-01-19T05:25:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-18T16:14:32.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/the-fang-playbook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The FANG Playbook&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Thompson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Each of the FANG companies was technically innovative in their own way […] but
    each of them […]depended to an incredible degree on products and infrastructure
    that already existed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘By owning the consumer entry point — the primary choke point — […] the FANG companies
    have been able to modularize and commoditize their suppliers’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘they are “aggregators” who start with the best customers and don’t really compete
    with incumbent companies, at least in the beginning. In fact, incumbents nearly
    universally benefit from the presence of aggregators, at least at first’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2016/01/nobody-wants-use-your-product/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Nobody Wants To Use Your Product&lt;/a&gt; by Goran Peuc&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘People are not really into using products. Any time spent by a user operating
    an interface, twisting knobs, pulling levers or tapping buttons is time wasted.
    Rather, people are more interested in the end result and in obtaining that result
    in the quickest, least intrusive and most efficient manner possible’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘When you think about it, do you really want to work on heating up your food, or
    do you just want your food to be hot? This is why microwave ovens can be found
    in basically every modern kitchen; it removes as much work as possible from the
    process of heating food. Of course, quite a lot of manufacturers still do not
    realize this and make their microwave ovens overly complicated with too many
    buttons and settings.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘This difference in approach — building for features versus building for result — can
    be seen in numerous products today, both digital and physical. The main reason
    why some products are great is that they take the load off of users and assist
    them in making decisions.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of great examples: Nest, Dropbox, Google search, Gov.uk, Amazon Dash, Apple
    updates vs. Adobe Flash updates, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.digitaltonto.com/2016/the-power-of-focus/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Power Of Focus&lt;/a&gt; by Greg Satell&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;IBM’s modern-day roots began as a function of refocusing. This cultural trait served
    IBM well when facing more innovative competition, by relying on superior execution.
    100 years later today, IBM is a longtime regular on S&amp;amp;P 500, in an age where
    the avg S&amp;amp;P lifespan is 10 years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mission drives strategy - ‘The truth is that your mission needs to drive your strategy,
    not the other way around. Genuine excellence requires passion, commitment and
    consistency. You can’t create that in a boardroom meeting or a strategy session.
    It takes focus over an extended period of time.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘To be a great performer — in any field — you simply have to do things better.
    That takes work. You need continually up your game over a period of years — or
    even decades — in order to get it right. That takes focus.’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://marketingland.com/a-cmos-view-amazons-neil-lindsay-says-customer-obsession-is-core-to-companys-dna-160153&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;A CMO’s View: Amazon’s Neil Lindsay Says Customer Obsession Is Core To Company’s
    DNA&lt;/a&gt; by Amy Gesenhues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Amazon makes the customer its top priority, aiming to create an experience so
    magical “… it disappears into our customer’s every day as their new normal.”’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Article stated takeaways: ‘Treat the customer as an individual, not a segment.
    Invest in earning trust, and never take it for granted. Think about making magic,
    more than making money.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘We always work backwards from the experience we believe an individual customer
    might appreciate, before we develop anything.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘I don’t formally “lead” the customer experience efforts, except in the same way
    as everyone in the company leads customer experience — it’s part of everyone’s
    job, every day.’&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://sixteenventures.com/customer-onboarding&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Secret to Successful Customer Onboarding&lt;/a&gt; by Lincoln Murphy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This article is about SAAS companies, but some good transferables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Onboarded should be defined by the customer, not the business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Know when the first value has been delivered, and drive the next level of engagement
    from that point.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talk to users to understand both of the above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lukew.com/ff/entry.asp?1954&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Mobile Web vs. Native Apps or Why You Want Both&lt;/a&gt; by Luke Wroblewski&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Important to effectively utilize both mobile web and mobile app&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;App has significantly better usage (retention), but web has significantly better
    reach (acquisition)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://stratechery.com/2016/the-fang-playbook/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The FANG Playbook&lt;/a&gt; by Ben Thompson&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Startups" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startups/"/>
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Weekly reads" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Weekly-reads/"/>
    
      <category term="Articles" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Articles/"/>
    
      <category term="Work" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Work/"/>
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Weekly reads, week of January 11 2016</title>
    <link href="http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jan11/2016/01/11/"/>
    <id>http://kiranakkineni.com/Weekly-reads-on-commute-2016-Jan11/2016/01/11/</id>
    <published>2016-01-12T05:25:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-19T21:10:45.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/the-story-behind-how-pocket-hit-20m-users-with-20-people/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Story Behind How Pocket Hit 20M Users with 20 People&lt;/a&gt; via First Round&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This one is worth reading multiple times.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small, understaffed companies have the opportunity to ruthlessly prioritize ‘the
    most important thing’. Don’t waste this opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All companies face the challenge of losing focus. When the entire company is working
    on fewer things, synergy effects result in big productivity gains.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leaders at every level over-index on their influence on the company’s culture.
    If it’s not working the way you want, look inward.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make your product dead simple. The easier it is to learn, the easier it is to engage.
    The easier it is to engage, the easier it is to find value.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Power users are a great collective PM. Utilize them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@producthunt/the-rise-and-fall-of-everest-the-app-b0d2e6cb594c#.72amnuqvu&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The Rise and Fall of Everest (the App)&lt;/a&gt; via Katherine Krug&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting upon the demise of a promising goal-accomplishment platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positives = great design, sales pitch, and investors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not so positive =&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many features outside of the core offering&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Site speed and tech debt matter…to a degree. Blaming the cofounder is a bit disingenuous,
    but what follows makes sense. Don’t overbet on big features that you haven’t
    tested for user interest (and that may be outside your core offering). Also,
    unit testing is really important (as is, one could argue, dogfooding).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Didn’t pick and effectively track core metrics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cash burn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Didn’t build a strong user feedback mechanism. Comments around not cracking motivation,
    etc, belie a lack of obsessive customer focus. Great comments later on regarding
    making it easy first, then fast, and then pretty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@blakeross/how-to-swallow-200-million-accidentally-c7d8ed57e625#.clwv50uef&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;How to Swallow $200 Million Accidentally&lt;/a&gt; by Blake Ross&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Judge a company’s priorities by it’s pixels” can also be pointed inwards. Judge
    your own company’s priorities by its pixels. Make your company’s pixels reflect
    it’s priorities.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Professional assassins don’t introduce themselves” — It makes sense to test and
    iterate on relatively small % of your population, so well-positioned competitors
    don’t jump into the fray before you’ve worked through the kinks. Easier to do
    for a small startup than a Facebook of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mckinsey.com/business-functions/marketing-and-sales/our-insights/building-a-design-driven-culture&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Building a design-driven culture&lt;/a&gt; by Jennifer Kilian, Hugo Sarrazin, and Hyo
  Yeon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;User empathy and UX focus produce compound returns over time. Many companies state
    that they focus on these things, but metrics and budgets state otherwise.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Understanding the ‘why’ behind customer activity is meaningfully more important
    than the ‘what’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move fast and iterate. “Consider Instagram, which launched by rolling out a product,
    learning which features were most popular (image sharing, commenting, and liking),
    and then relaunching a stripped-down version.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.washingtonpost.stfi.re/business/economy/shoppers-are-choosing-experiences-over-stuff-and-thats-bad-news-for-retailers/2016/01/07/eaa80b5a-b4a7-11e5-a76a-0b5145e8679a_story.html?sf=oorodr#aa&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;Shoppers are choosing experiences over stuff, and that’s bad news for retailers&lt;/a&gt;
  by Sarah Halzack&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retail product sales were weak over the holiday season; however air travel and
    restaurant sales were relatively strong. Hypothesis is that this represents a
    millenial-driven mix shift in preferences towards experiences over materials.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Physical retailers are experimenting with incorporating more engaging interactions
    into the shopping experience. Nordstrom allows users to design their own shoes.
    Lululemon enabling exercise. Urban Outfitters and Pizza?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cbinsights.com/blog/startup-failure-post-mortem/#2015update&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;More reads 146 Startup Failure Post-Mortems&lt;/a&gt; via CB Insights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of good lessons in here, but the biggest takeaway is that there are a lot
    of ways that things can go wrong, and a lot of luck involved.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Until product-market fit is achieved (and long after), maintaining speed and discipline
    creates the greatest odds of success.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://tomtunguz.com/how-many-funnels-in-your-product/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;How Many Funnels Does Your Startup’s Product Have?&lt;/a&gt; by Tomasz Tunguz&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fairly straightforward read → map / know / understand your funnels&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://firstround.com/review/the-story-behind-how-pocket-hit-20m-users-with-20-people/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;The St
    
    </summary>
    
      <category term="Lists" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/categories/Lists/"/>
    
    
      <category term="Startups" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Startups/"/>
    
      <category term="Kiran Akkineni" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Kiran-Akkineni/"/>
    
      <category term="Weekly reads" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Weekly-reads/"/>
    
      <category term="Articles" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Articles/"/>
    
      <category term="Work" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Work/"/>
    
      <category term="Product management" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Product-management/"/>
    
      <category term="Strategy" scheme="http://kiranakkineni.com/tags/Strategy/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
